Hey guys, welcome back.
Now let's talk about why we need
to really think about incremental processing of the raw
to curated and curated to aggregate it.
As I said before, you see whatever you have in raw,
we get trans on and come to curated, right?
Of course, when you're doing this, we had some rejections
as well, if you remember the transformation.
But the point is that, let's say if you have data for,
let's say, uh, 2025 from January
to June, okay, six months, all the data for Jan two,
June of 2025 will come to curated.
You agree with that? And all the data from curated Jan
to June, 2025 will go
to aggregated when you run the third job.
I hope that is very, very clear.
Now, let's say this job number one is
run again, and by then you had July's data.
2025 July data, you had enabled the incremental,
you set the job type to current,
and it pulled the July data into raw.
So in raw, what do you have?
Now you have data from Jan to July.
Now, okay, before you had Jan to June,
now you have data from Jan to July.
I have one additional month. So when you process the data
from RAW to Curated, you have all the data from Jan
to July now, but you had already processed
Jan to June before.
Why do you need to process the Jan to June?
Again, it's not required. That is all done.
So incrementally you should be processing only the July
data, which is coming into law.
That is the reason we need to think about
how we can pull data incrementally.
Also, what's, what's the point of processing it again?
I mean, you are unnecessarily, you are spending money
and time on processing it, right?
I mean, it'll happen. It'll just read all the data
and, uh, load to curate it again, it, it'll over the data.
You can do the historical processing
every month, but what is the point?
It'll unnecessarily take longer time every time, right?
There's no point. You don't wanna waste
resources, time and money.
So if we can find a way to just pull the July data from raw
and loaded to curated again, see, curated also has
also has your Jan, June, July, right?
So you want to just
load the July data again from curated to aggregate.
I hope this much is very, very clear, right?
As to what I'm trying to explain here, why we need
to pull data incrementally.
Now, with this background, very, very solid.
Let's see how we can implement that. Okay?
A very, very simple, uh, solution for this.
There are multiple ways of doing this, multiple solutions,
and what I'll now talk about is very,
very important in the next studio, in fact, okay?
This is one of the most important concepts in Glue. Okay?
The next video is gonna be full of concepts
and practical things.
There's a lot, okay? It's a short video,
but there's a lot. It's a
Dense video.
See, I could have skipped the next video, you know,
for incremental processing.
I could have chosen our easier way also,
but I wanted to show you the benefits of using Glue.
What I'm gonna be talking about next
is something unique to Glue, okay?
It's called as a job bookmark, and it is unique to Glue.
And in the interviews,
you could be asked if the company is using Glue bookmarks,
they will ask you this question.
If they're not using it, they will not ask you.
But if they are using it, they will ask you.
And my students who have cracked interviews have told
this is a regular question.
So for me, I could have just given you simple solution
and, you know, thinking that, okay,
my students might feel it difficult
and so might just skip the course
or, you know, drop out of the course midway.
But if I have that thought in mind, I cannot really
help the other people who are really, really
focused and serious.
You know, I and I,
and I hope you are in that category where you know
where you are really focused and serious.
And so my humble request to you is next video.
Watch it once, twice, twice.
Make clear notes, practice it.
Then towards the end, share your own notes, okay?
Because this is gonna be extremely important again.